[
  {
    "question": "Who was the founder of the Maurya Empire?",
    "options": ["Ashoka", "Chandragupta Maurya", "Samudragupta", "Harsha"],
    "answer": "Chandragupta Maurya"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which dynasty ruled over India during the 12th and 13th centuries?",
    "options": [
      "Pala Dynasty",
      "Chola Dynasty",
      "Gupta Dynasty",
      "Vijayanagara Empire"
    ],
    "answer": "Pala Dynasty"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first British Governor-General of India?",
    "options": [
      "Lord Canning",
      "Lord Curzon",
      "Lord Hastings",
      "Warren Hastings"
    ],
    "answer": "Warren Hastings"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which battle marked the beginning of the Indian National Movement?",
    "options": [
      "Battle of Plassey",
      "Battle of Buxar",
      "Battle of Waterloo",
      "Battle of Saratoga"
    ],
    "answer": "Battle of Plassey"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the leader of the non-violent civil disobedience movement in India?",
    "options": [
      "Mahatma Gandhi",
      "Subhas Chandra Bose",
      "Jawaharlal Nehru",
      "Vallabhbhai Patel"
    ],
    "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which act transferred power from the British to the Indians?",
    "options": [
      "Government of India Act 1919",
      "Government of India Act 1935",
      "Indian Independence Act 1947",
      "Rowlatt Act 1919"
    ],
    "answer": "Indian Independence Act 1947"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of independent India?",
    "options": [
      "Jawaharlal Nehru",
      "Vallabhbhai Patel",
      "Lal Bahadur Shastri",
      "Narendra Modi"
    ],
    "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which dynasty was known for its patronage of art and culture during the medieval period?",
    "options": [
      "Chalukya Dynasty",
      "Chola Dynasty",
      "Gupta Dynasty",
      "Maratha Empire"
    ],
    "answer": "Chalukya Dynasty"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Mughal Emperor who constructed the Taj Mahal?",
    "options": ["Akbar", "Babur", "Jahangir", "Shah Jahan"],
    "answer": "Shah Jahan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ancient civilization flourished in the Indus Valley region?",
    "options": [
      "Mesopotamian Civilization",
      "Egyptian Civilization",
      "Indus Valley Civilization",
      "Harappan Civilization"
    ],
    "answer": "Indus Valley Civilization"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first female Governor-General of India?",
    "options": [
      "Rajkumari Amrit Kaur",
      "Vijayalakshmi Pandit",
      "Sarojini Naidu",
      "Indira Gandhi"
    ],
    "answer": "Rajkumari Amrit Kaur"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which battle led to the death of Aurangzeb?",
    "options": [
      "Battle of Panipat",
      "Battle of Haldighati",
      "Battle of Plassey",
      "Battle of Deeg"
    ],
    "answer": "Battle of Deeg"
  }
]
